Hiren Patel

Phone: 2049221305

Address: #B7-1530B 20th Street, Brandon, MB, R7B2M6.

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/hiren-patel-089b1b96/

Email: hirenpatel6777@gmail.com

Over 5+ years experience in IT industry specifically in UI/UX Designer. a Bachelor of Engineering degree in computer science. Top-notch communication and multitasking skills with a proactive mentality and flexible approach to problem-solving. Goal-oriented and proficient team player motivated to increase abilities and make a positive impact on team projects.

EXPERIENCE

PBC Multimedia.- Brandon, MB, Canada.

Dec 2020-Current

Web Designer+SEO

- · Conceptualizing creative ideas with clients.
- Working with different content management systems.
- Communicating design ideas using flows, process flows, site maps.
- · Incorporating functionalities and features into websites.
- · E-commerce website.
- Maintaining the appearance of websites by enforcing content standards.
- Designing visual imagery for websites and ensuring that they are in line with branding for clients.
- Tools:- Adobe Dreamweaver, Adobe Photoshop, Sublime, brackets, Adobe Illustrator, Duda web platform, Google Analytics, Google Adwords, Google Search Console, SEMrush
- Language and Skills:- HTML, CSS, Wordpress, Jquery, Angular Js, JavaScript, Social Media Marketing, Photo Retouching

Sanah Infosolutions Pvt.Ltd.- Vadodara,India.

Web Designer

· Conceptualizing creative ideas with clients.

- Working with different content management systems.
- · Communicating design ideas using flows, process flows, site maps.
- Incorporating functionalities and features into websites.
- Designing sample pages including colors and fonts.
- · Preparing design plans and presenting the website structure.
- Testing and improving the design of the website.
- Establishing design guidelines, standards, and best practices.
- · Maintaining the appearance of websites by enforcing content standards.
- Designing visual imagery for websites and ensuring that they are in line with branding for clients.
- Tools:- Adobe Dreamweaver, Adobe Photoshop, Sublime, brackets, Adobe Illustrator
- Language and Skills:- PHP,HTML, CSS, Wordpress, Jquery, Angular Js, JavaScript, Social Media Marketing, Photo Retouching

Aug 2017-Feb 2020

PriyaSharm Software Pvt. Ltd.-Vadodara, India.

Web Designer

- Testing and improving the design of the website.
- Maintaining the appearance of websites by enforcing content standards.
- · Email blast design using photoshop.
- Tools:- Adobe Dreamweaver, Adobe Photoshop
- Language and Skills:- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Social Media Marketing, Photo Retouching

LenDen Club(Innofin Solutions Private Limited)-Mumbai, India. *Jul 2015-Jul 2016*Web Designer

- Testing and improving the design of the website.
- Communicating design ideas using flows, process flows, site maps.
- Maintaining the appearance of websites by enforcing content standards.
- Email blast design using photoshop.
- Tools:- Adobe Dreamweaver, Adobe Photoshop, Sublime, brackets, Adobe Illustrator
- Language and Skills:- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Social Media Marketing, Photo Retouching

EDUCATION

R.R Institution Of Technology (VTU) (Bangalore- India) Aug 2009-May 2013 Bachelor of engineering (Computer Science)

SKILLS

- **Technical Skills**: C, C++,My-SQL, HTML,XML, CSS, Bootstrap, Java script, jQuery, AJAX, Angular JS, RESTful APIs, PHP, GitHub, Internet protocols
- Soft Skills: Team player, Self-learner, Advanced problem-solver, Innovative, Creative, Good Communication
- Software Applications: My-SQLserver, Git, Microsoft office, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator
- Operating Systems: Windows 10/8/7/XP, Linux, Mac OS

WORKSHOPS

- Attended certified course in Tops Technologies(Web Designer)
- Attended workshop on Hackathon event in Mumbai.
- Participate in the event NCCIT-2013 held by RRIT college.

VOLUNTEERING

- Active Member Of BAPS Youth Club.
- Leader in Ozone event Organized by RRIT college.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.